<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jpmarindiaz</title>
    <link>/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on jpmarindiaz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking data types for humans</title>
      <link>/2018-01-15-rethinking-data-types-for-humans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018-01-15-rethinking-data-types-for-humans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every visualization library out there would benefit a lot from having tidy representations for the input data formats they need. Whether it is geographical data or texts, identifying tidy data as the inputs for visualizations is a huge gain for the developers and the end users, validations can be more easily introduced and transition from one visualization software to other would be smoother if the visualizations had a common tidy data interface.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducción a las pseudo-visualizaciones</title>
      <link>/2018-01-14-introducci%C3%B3n-a-las-pseudo-visualizaciones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018-01-14-introducci%C3%B3n-a-las-pseudo-visualizaciones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pseudoviz es una descripción de alto nivel sobre las cualidades descriptivas y funcionales con las que cuenta una visualización.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usa esbozos para representar visualizaciones estereotípicas de manera que sean entendidas por humanos. Usualmente se obvian detalles esenciales para la creación de la visualización bien sea por propiedades particulares del software que se use para visualizar o porque los detalles se pueden entender como una variación de la visualización. Los detalles omitidos pueden ser leyendas, títulos, ticks, rayas o anotaciones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El objetivo de usar una pseudoviz es ayudar en procesos creativos o científicos de comunicación de datos independiente del ambiente de desarrollo de manera eficiente con la definición de borradores y esquemas que muestran los principios clave de una visualización antes de su implementación.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Se pueden usar en guías de visualización de datos y en publicaciones que muestren diferentes tipos de visualización, así como en la planeación de páneles de control (dashboards) o historias de periodismo de datos para trazar un mapa de ruta antes de la implementación final. En el proceso de creación se pueden acompañar de anotaciones de texto que describan detalles específicos como interactividad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No existe un estándar para la creación de pseudoviz ya que es independiente de la estructura de datos que representan o el mecanismo de renderización. Es recomendable, en el diseño de una pseudoviz mapear los posibles tipos o estructura de datos de entrada que una eventual visualización implementada debería tener.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing pseudo-visualizations</title>
      <link>/2018-01-14-introducing-pseudo-visualizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018-01-14-introducing-pseudo-visualizations/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A pseudo-visualization is a high-level representation of the functional and descriptive parts of a visualization. It uses sketches and data types to represent stereotypical visualizations that can be understood by humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pseudo-visualization helps creative processes or communication of data driven messages independent of the visualization development environment (materials, software packages or design). Their sketches and specification provide an efficient guide to exchanges ideas around data driven messages and key components before the implementation of the visualization itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a pseudo-visualization details like legends, titles, ticks or annotations are omitted. These details are usually design choices or constrains determined by the visualization designer or by software use to visualize data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pseudo-visualizations can be used in the design of data based interfaces or reports like dashboards or data journalism pieces. They can be particularly helpful in the design process by providing an implementation roadmap around the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data that is actually required for the different parts of the report or dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tools that can be used to generate the specific visualization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One could use pseudo-visualizations for wireframing control panels and data driven stories. The wireframes can include annotations on top of the pseudo-visualizations to describe specific details like the input data and the desired interactivity features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once iterations around the full sketch evolve into a compeling data driven story and they are approved, the implementation phase can start. Notice that the implementation phase is an iterative process. That is because at the end, no matter how visualization designer envisions the final product, the visualization is constrained by the data availability and the data types used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There exists not a single standard for the creation of a pseudo-visualization, in fact, any doodle that resembles some data mapped into visual clues will work just fine in the design process, at least for the visual part since it is also recommended to incorporate the data structure and types that would be used while creating the final visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of galleries of visualization types available. Be aware that identifying also the input data structures and types is part of the pseudo-visualization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pseudoviz&#34;&gt;Pseudoviz&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pseudoviz is a gallery of visualization types. Not only does it provide more than 200 visualization types but also the data structures need to build those visualizations in a tidy format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pseudoviz.jpmarindiaz.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./img/pseudoviz/pseudoviz-gallery.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-visualization-galleries&#34;&gt;Other visualization galleries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://datavizcatalogue.com/index.html&#34;&gt;https://datavizcatalogue.com/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://datavizproject.com/&#34;&gt;http://datavizproject.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://python-graph-gallery.com/&#34;&gt;https://python-graph-gallery.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ft-interactive/chart-doctor/blob/master/visual-vocabulary/Visual-vocabulary.pdf&#34;&gt;https://github.com/ft-interactive/chart-doctor/blob/master/visual-vocabulary/Visual-vocabulary.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.r-graph-gallery.com/all-graphs/&#34;&gt;http://www.r-graph-gallery.com/all-graphs/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guides.library.duke.edu/datavis/vis_types&#34;&gt;https://guides.library.duke.edu/datavis/vis_types&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self service interactive visualization apps with Shiny and Htmlwidgets</title>
      <link>/2018-01-14-self-service-interactive-visualization-apps-with-shiny-and-htmlwidgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018-01-14-self-service-interactive-visualization-apps-with-shiny-and-htmlwidgets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a post about building interactive visualization apps with Shiny and Htmlwidgets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The status of my R packages</title>
      <link>/2018-01-10-the-status-of-my-r-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018-01-10-the-status-of-my-r-packages/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I have been writing different packages for a while now. I have never tried to publish them on CRAN becuse I thought they were never good enough, so most of the time I didn&amp;rsquo;t even bother to document them properly or even to build unit tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing this now because, as new years resolution I commited to polish and properly publish my most promising packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here it is, I am putting the word out and we will see at the end of the year how many packages I manage to make available to other curious R Users. Here they are in alphabetical order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;cloudinary&#34;&gt;cloudinaRy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An R package to interact with Cloudinary from R&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;datafringe&#34;&gt;datafringe&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It adds dictionaries to a dataframe in a new type of objects that I call a Fringe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;deduplicate&#34;&gt;deduplicate&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An attempt to make data deduplication easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;d3plus&#34;&gt;d3plus&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An htmlwidget to make tidy visualizations with d3plus.js&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;dmaps&#34;&gt;dmaps&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An htmlwidget to build interactive maps based on datamaps.js
It will be renamed shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;dsappmodules&#34;&gt;dsAppModules&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modules to make development of shiny apps easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;geodata&#34;&gt;geodata&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R Package that has geodata ready to be plotted in different formats. The advantage is that it intends to have geographical codes for regions that are standard for each country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;imteractive&#34;&gt;imteractive&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make interactive images using d3. Add tooltips and other interactive elements to static images in html.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;geomagic&#34;&gt;geomagic&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tidy wrapper for making maps in ggplot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;mop&#34;&gt;mop&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A package to clean data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;pseudoviz&#34;&gt;pseudoviz&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A package/gallery of visualization types. It has now some basic funcions to make graph recommendations based on some input data. It relies on [homodatum][./#homodatum]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;homodatum&#34;&gt;homodatum&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe in the tidyverse and the power of defining column types. However, there are data types that are still thought and created for computers to understand and not for humans.
Homodatum tries to solve this issue by introducing data types for humans. Instead of strings like computers think, we think in categories or texts. Instead of int we think in countries codes and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ggmagic&#34;&gt;ggmagic&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tidy wrapper for ggplots. Is an attempt to make visualizations work out of the box for different column types.
Warning: Might be considered a stupid package because it only wraps ggplot functions.
It does help me make data questioning way faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;hgchmagic&#34;&gt;hgchmagic&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tidy wrapper for all possible highcharter functions. Same idea behind ggmagic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;paletero&#34;&gt;paletero&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its goal is to make it easier to create palettes and map different data types to colors. Still not sure if it is a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rneo4jutils&#34;&gt;RNeo4jUtils&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrapper utilities to be used along with RNeo4j package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;shinysteps&#34;&gt;shinysteps&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shiny layout to create steps or pages apps. The ones that you go from one page to the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;shi18ny&#34;&gt;shi18ny&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introduces internationalization to shiny apps using some basic translation and custom translations for different languages using YAML files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;sigmagraph&#34;&gt;sigmaGraph&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An htmlwidget to build interactive network visualizations using sigma.js and linkourious.js&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;timelinejs&#34;&gt;timelinejs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An htmlwidget for timeline.js to be used with tidy data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;some-older-attempts&#34;&gt;Some older attempts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t worked on these packages in a while, but might re___ at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;captureWidget&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;other-planned-packages&#34;&gt;Other planned packages&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tidytweenr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewriting pystr::pystr_format function in base R</title>
      <link>/2017-07-20-rewriting-pystrpystr_format-function-in-base-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017-07-20-rewriting-pystrpystr_format-function-in-base-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recurrently want to render templates like this one: &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Hola {first_name} {last_name}&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; with values in a list, like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;template &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;Hola {first_name} {last_name}&amp;quot;
renderMyTemplate(template, list(first_name = &amp;quot;JP&amp;quot;, last_name=&amp;quot;Marín Díaz&amp;quot;))
# &amp;quot;Hola JP Marín Díaz&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was using the &lt;code&gt;pystr&lt;/code&gt; package for this. Actually I was using the whole package for only one of its functions: &lt;code&gt;pystr_format()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, we realized the the package was no &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Ironholds/pystr/issues/11&#34;&gt;longer maintained&lt;/a&gt; for the latest R version. Some efforts to keep it alive in CRAN are on the way. For those like myself who only need to format templates here is function to do exactly this using only base R. It works for data.frames too and it happens to be faster than the good old &lt;code&gt;pystr_format()&lt;/code&gt;, at least in the silly benchmark I performed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;
tpl_format &amp;lt;- function(tpl, l){
  if(class(l) == &amp;quot;list&amp;quot;){
    listToNameValue &amp;lt;- function(l){
      mapply(function(i,j) list(name = j, value = i), l, names(l), SIMPLIFY = FALSE)
    }
    f &amp;lt;- function(tpl,l){
      gsub(paste0(&amp;quot;{&amp;quot;,l$name,&amp;quot;}&amp;quot;), l$value, tpl, fixed = TRUE)
    }
    return( Reduce(f,listToNameValue(l), init = tpl))
  }
  if(class(l) == &amp;quot;data.frame&amp;quot;){
    myTranspose &amp;lt;- function(x) lapply(1:nrow(x), function(i) lapply(d, &amp;quot;[[&amp;quot;, i))
    return( unlist(lapply(myTranspose(l), function(l, tpl) rep_tpl(tpl, l), tpl = tpl)) )
  }
}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r test&#34;&gt;tpl &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;{name} fdla {last} {other}&amp;quot;
l &amp;lt;- list(name = &amp;quot;NAME&amp;quot;, last = &amp;quot;LAST&amp;quot;, other = &amp;quot;OTHER&amp;quot;,  mote = &amp;quot;fdasf&amp;quot;)
d &amp;lt;- data.frame(name = c(&amp;quot;ana&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;jp&amp;quot;), last = c(&amp;quot;heran&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;marin&amp;quot;), n = c(1,2))

rep_tpl(tpl, l)
rep_tpl(tpl, d)
pystr::pystr_format(tpl, l)
pystr::pystr_format(tpl, d)

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;microbenchmark::microbenchmark(
  rep_tpl(tpl, l),
  pystr::pystr_format(tpl, l)
)
#Unit: microseconds
#                        expr    min       lq      mean   median       uq     max neval
#             rep_tpl(tpl, l) 42.500  47.8885  65.65773  53.3420  58.1765 399.373   100
# pystr::pystr_format(tpl, l) 95.278 105.8865 131.94053 118.6685 128.6940 542.297   100
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;microbenchmark::microbenchmark(
  rep_tpl(tpl, d),
  pystr::pystr_format(tpl, d)
)
#Unit: microseconds
#                        expr     min      lq     mean   median       uq      max neval
#             rep_tpl(tpl, d) 154.627 165.006 203.1093 177.5755 210.0555  586.461   100
# pystr::pystr_format(tpl, d) 394.064 416.068 493.6397 443.0620 509.1740 1027.248   100
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my session Info&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; sessionInfo()
R version 3.3.2 (2016-10-31)
Platform: x86_64-apple-darwin13.4.0 (64-bit)
Running under: macOS Sierra 10.12.5

locale:
[1] en_US.UTF-8/en_US.UTF-8/en_US.UTF-8/C/en_US.UTF-8/en_US.UTF-8

attached base packages:
[1] stats     graphics  grDevices utils     datasets  methods   base     

loaded via a namespace (and not attached):
 [1] colorspace_1.3-2       scales_0.4.1           microbenchmark_1.4-2.1
 [4] lazyeval_0.2.0         plyr_1.8.4             tools_3.3.2           
 [7] gtable_0.2.0           tibble_1.3.3           Rcpp_0.12.11.4        
[10] ggplot2_2.2.1          grid_3.3.2             rlang_0.1.1           
[13] munsell_0.4.3          pystr_2.0.0   
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S3 bucket public access policy</title>
      <link>/2017-06-17-s3-bucket-public-access-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017-06-17-s3-bucket-public-access-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Use this policy for making a bucket public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    &amp;quot;Version&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;2012-10-17&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;Statement&amp;quot;: [
        {
            &amp;quot;Sid&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;AllowPublicRead&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;Effect&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Allow&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;Principal&amp;quot;: {
                &amp;quot;AWS&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;*&amp;quot;
            },
            &amp;quot;Action&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;s3:GetObject&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;Resource&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;arn:aws:s3:::mybucket/*&amp;quot;
        }
    ]
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A viztype a day...</title>
      <link>/2017-05-10-a-viztype-a-day.../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017-05-10-a-viztype-a-day.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are 235 days left in the year. I will start today to post a new visualization type every (almost) day on twitter with the hashtag #viztype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a bunch of different visualization types. Most people can recall only a handful but in reality there are a couple hundred already out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow the conversation around visualization types please follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/viztype?src=hash&#34;&gt;#viztype&lt;/a&gt; on twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently I cannot commit to tweet every single day. Sometimes I tweet a viztype twice a day and sometimes I forget to do it while on conferences or weekends. Here they are all gathered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-10 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/862337558256115714&#34;&gt;Pie chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-11 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/862742294499282944&#34;&gt;Waffle Chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-12 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/863059205996990464&#34;&gt;Bulseye graph&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-13 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/863615772223971329&#34;&gt;Dial Chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-14 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/863875933836517377&#34;&gt;Nightingale Rose Chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-15 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/864146460530532357&#34;&gt;Vertical Bar Chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-16 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/864522123649220608&#34;&gt;Sankey Diagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-17 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/864822201043767297&#34;&gt;Grouped Bar Chart Vertical&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-18 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/865247673107873793&#34;&gt;Stacked Vertical Bar Chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-20 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/865956055850811392&#34;&gt;Slope Graph&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-21 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/866492774249574401&#34;&gt;Gauge Chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-22 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/866832504640110592&#34;&gt;Lollipops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-23 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/867169752774393856&#34;&gt;Area Chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-24 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/867564361006563329&#34;&gt;Choropleth Numeric&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-25 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/867849629085253632&#34;&gt;Pyramid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-26 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/868179211663450115&#34;&gt;Horizon Graph Multiples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-27 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/868590560730165248&#34;&gt;Horizontal Bar Chart with Colors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-28 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/868918502974832640&#34;&gt;Horizonal Lollipops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-29 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/869361021932142592&#34;&gt;Line Chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-05-30 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/869667606957092864&#34;&gt;Normalized Stacked Areal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-03 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/871051834672152577&#34;&gt;Geo heatmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-05 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/871730237033336832&#34;&gt;Treemap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-05 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/871840826573418496&#34;&gt;Watterfall Chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-06 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/872093816597172224&#34;&gt;Arcs Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-07 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/872453664757174272&#34;&gt;Arc Diagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-08 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/872847195724279810&#34;&gt;Bullet Charts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-09 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/873283652620308481&#34;&gt;Vertical Normalized Stacked Chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-10 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/873514050155622400&#34;&gt;Multiple Lines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-11 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/874062177149341696&#34;&gt;Calendar Heatmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-02-12 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/874349138057596931&#34;&gt;Choropleth Map Categoric&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-13 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/874599325585862660&#34;&gt;Grouped Bar Chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-14 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/875061666500812800&#34;&gt;Bubble Charts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-15 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/875370156691738625&#34;&gt;Lollipops difference chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-16 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/875715040254586882&#34;&gt;Marimekko&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-17 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/876114743035133952&#34;&gt;Bar Chart Coloured Vertical&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-18 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/876525138942013442&#34;&gt;Wordtree&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-19 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/876789344027250689&#34;&gt;3D grouped scatter plot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-20 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/877172762498015232&#34;&gt;Grouped Horizontal Bar Chart Colors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-22 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/877980303217668097&#34;&gt;Bivariate Choropleth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-23 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/878271226468282368&#34;&gt;Subway&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-27 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/879724196636618752&#34;&gt;Bullet Charts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-28 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/880104259890679808&#34;&gt;Cartogram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-29 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/880443442639327232&#34;&gt;Area Blocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-06-30 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/880850390052466689&#34;&gt;Two y-axis lines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-07-04 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/882246790246010883&#34;&gt;3D Bars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-07-05 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/882641217498042368&#34;&gt;Hexbin Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-07-06 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/882945292827590656&#34;&gt;Parallel Coords&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-07-07 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/883369255923838976&#34;&gt;Network Rings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-07-10 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/884452114398937089&#34;&gt;Stacked Area Normalized&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-07-11 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/884968851158519808&#34;&gt;Stacked Stepped Area Normalized&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-07-12 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/885245445416640513&#34;&gt;Pairs Plot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-07-13 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/885483418741608448&#34;&gt;Partition Chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-07-14 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/885904484991479809&#34;&gt;Stacked Circular Bar Chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-07-17 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/887049227960037379&#34;&gt;Bars with Target Line&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-07-18 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/887492049372684288&#34;&gt;Quiver Plot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-07-19 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/887662296423682048&#34;&gt;Depth Area Chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-07-20 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/888080903720841216&#34;&gt;Vertical Stacked Normalized Bar Chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-07-22 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/888770702572216320&#34;&gt;Ternary Plot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-07-23 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/889156576682143744&#34;&gt;QQplot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017-07-24 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/889529650065682433&#34;&gt;Venn Diagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command line cheatsheet</title>
      <link>/2016-12-26-command-line-cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 08:45:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016-12-26-command-line-cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;merge-files-into-one&#34;&gt;Merge files into one&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1653063/how-do-i-include-a-blank-line-between-files-im-concatenating-with-cat&#34;&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1653063/how-do-i-include-a-blank-line-between-files-im-concatenating-with-cat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ls -1 | while read f; do cat &amp;quot;$f&amp;quot;; done &amp;gt; ../../archive.json
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gitbook cheatsheet</title>
      <link>/2016-12-02-gitbook-cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 18:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016-12-02-gitbook-cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-a-book&#34;&gt;Create a book&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitBook can setup a boilerplate book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gitbook init
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wish to create the book into a new directory, you can do so by running gitbook init ./directory&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preview and serve your book using: &lt;code&gt;gitbook serve&lt;/code&gt;
Or build the static website using: &lt;code&gt;gitbook build&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generate a PDF file &lt;code&gt;gitbook pdf ./ ./mybook.pdf&lt;/code&gt;
Generate an ePub file &lt;code&gt;gitbook epub ./ ./mybook.epub&lt;/code&gt;
Generate a Mobi file &lt;code&gt;gitbook mobi ./ ./mybook.mobi&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;plugins&#34;&gt;Plugins&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &amp;quot;plugins&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;hide-published-with&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;addcssjs&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;sharing&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;footnote-string-to-number&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;richquotes&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;emphasize&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;image-captions&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;atoc&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;katex&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;autosize-iframe&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;collapsible-menu&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;printlinks&amp;quot;],
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;plugin&#34;&gt;Plugin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;image-caption&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;            &amp;quot;attributes&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;width&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;300&amp;quot; },
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit, sed do eiusmod
tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam,
quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo
consequat. [1]

| Tables        | Are           | Cool  |
| ------------- |:-------------:| -----:|
| col 3 is      | right-aligned | $1600 |
| col 2 is      | centered      |   $12 |
| zebra stripes | are neat      |    $1 |

Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse
cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non
proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.

This is some text[^1].

[^1]: Some *crazy* footnote definition.


## Rich quotes

&amp;gt; **Info** Info


&amp;gt; **Note** Note


&amp;gt; **Tag** Tag


&amp;gt; **Comment** Comment

&amp;gt; **Hint** Hint

&amp;gt; **Success** Success

&amp;gt; **Warning** Warning

&amp;gt; **Caution** Caution

&amp;gt; **Danger** Danger

&amp;gt; **Quote** Quote

## Text highlight

This text is {% em %}highlighted !{% endem %}

This text is {% em %}highlighted with **markdown**!{% endem %}

This text is {% em type=&amp;quot;green&amp;quot; %}highlighted in green!{% endem %}

This text is {% em type=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot; %}highlighted in red!{% endem %}

This text is {% em color=&amp;quot;#ff0000&amp;quot; %}highlighted with a custom color!{% endem %}

![imagesss](assets/images/business-sprint.png)

![Alt text][id]

[id]: assets/images/business-backlog.png  &amp;quot;Optional title attribute&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>git lfs</title>
      <link>/2016-12-02-git-lfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 18:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016-12-02-git-lfs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For MACOS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew install git-lfs
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select the file types you&amp;rsquo;d like Git LFS to manage (or directly edit your .gitattributes). You can configure additional file extensions at anytime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git lfs track &amp;quot;*.largefileext&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commit and push to GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add file.largefileext
git commit -m &amp;quot;Add design file&amp;quot;
git push origin master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git/github things I keep googling</title>
      <link>/2016-10-24-git/github-things-i-keep-googling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 10:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016-10-24-git/github-things-i-keep-googling/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-change-origin-remote&#34;&gt;How to change origin remote&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git remote set-url origin git://new.url.here&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;git-discard-uncommited-changes&#34;&gt;Git discard uncommited changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For unstaged changes &lt;code&gt;git checkout -- .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For staged and unstaged &lt;code&gt;git reset --hard&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human vs Machine</title>
      <link>/human-vs-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 09:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/human-vs-machine/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;notes-on-things-humans-can-do-that-machines-don-t-at-least-not-yet&#34;&gt;Notes on things humans can do that machines don&amp;rsquo;t (at least not yet)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invent words (2016-10-24)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incorporate words of other languages (2016-10-24)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Español</title>
      <link>/espanol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 06:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/espanol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Normalmente escribo en inglés.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Escribo en español sobre temas regionales de Colombia o América Latina, o cualquier otro en el cual necesite ser más fluido.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mantendré acá una lista con los contenidos más relevantes en español.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SublimeText setup</title>
      <link>/2016-10-17-sublimetext-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 11:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016-10-17-sublimetext-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sublime packages&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color Helper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EncodingHelper (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/titoBouzout/EncodingHelper&#34;&gt;https://github.com/titoBouzout/EncodingHelper&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launch sublime from terminal (MACOS)
&lt;a href=&#34;http://olivierlacan.com/posts/launch-sublime-text-3-from-the-command-line/&#34;&gt;http://olivierlacan.com/posts/launch-sublime-text-3-from-the-command-line/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ln -s &amp;quot;/Applications/Sublime Text.app/Contents/SharedSupport/bin/subl&amp;quot; /usr/local/bin/subl
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>